getpocket.com 2014-06-28

# Pocket: Privacy Policy

#### _Posted May 28, 2014_

This notice describes the Privacy Policy that applies to all information collected or submitted when you install or use the Pocket™ application or any of the other proprietary software applications or services we provide, and when you visit our website (all of which are referred to collectively herein as the "Pocket Technologies"). The Pocket Technologies are owned and operated by Read It Later, Inc. (referred to herein as "we," "us," "our," "Read It Later" or "Pocket"), which has developed applications and services for use in connection with a variety of devices and platforms, including without limitation, Windows, Mac, iPhone, iPad, Kindle Fire, Android, BlackBerry, Windows phone, Chrome, Safari, Firefox and other mobile devices and computers. 

We understand your concerns about privacy. We want you to understand what types of information we collect and what may happen to that information if you install the Pocket application, visit the Pocket Website or use any of the Pocket Technologies. 

Our Privacy Policy includes the following provisions, and you can jump to each by selecting the links below: 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, you should contact us at [privacy@getpocket.com](mailto:privacy@getpocket.com). Alternatively, you may contact us at:  
**Read It Later, Inc.  
731 Market Street, Suite 410   
San Francisco, CA 94103   
**

#### USER ACCOUNTS AND COLLECTION OF INFORMATION

You are not required to create a user account or provide any personal information in order to visit the Pocket website. You are required to create a user account, however, to use our application or to use some of our services, such as saving videos, articles or other content to Pocket. 

During registration, you are required to provide a username, password and valid email address. You may also be asked to provide certain categories of personally identifiable information, such as your name, address, date of birth and other contact information. If you choose to subscribe to our paid subscription service, you will be asked to provide credit card or other payment information. This information may be transmitted to a third party payment processor to enable us to process your payments. Such third party processors’ use of your personal information is governed by their respective privacy policies which may or may not contain privacy protections as protective as this privacy policy. 

If you choose to share any videos, articles, or other content with another person, we will ask you to provide a valid email address for that person. We may also ask you to provide your username and password for third party websites in order to access the articles and information published on such sites. We also collect information if you contact us for support or help, submit an application or otherwise communicate with us. The information which you supply to us enables us to customize and enhance the services we provide to you. In addition, it helps us communicate with you about our news, events, promotions and new products. 

#### PASSIVE COLLECTION OF INFORMATION

In addition to the information that you provide to us when you register for a user account, we collect information about the URLs, titles and content of the web pages and other information you save to Pocket. The types of passive information we collect includes your Internet Service Provider, IP address, browser type, device type, settings, time zone, language, and other information related to the manner in which you access the Pocket Technologies. We also collect information about your use of the Pocket Technologies, such as what you have read or viewed, which device you used to have accessed such content, what you choose to save to Pocket, what you have searched for in Pocket, and what you choose to share with others. We compile aggregated data by combining information from many users, without including any information that could be used to identify you or anyone else by name. 

In addition to the methods described above, we may also collect information using cookies or other technologies. Cookies are small files stored on your device or hard drive that assist us in providing customized services; for example, the use of cookies allows us to reduce the frequency with which you will need to enter your username or password. Additionally, in some cases, certain functionalities are only feasible through the use of a cookie. You may decline our cookies if your browser permits, although in that case you may not be able to use certain features, you may be required to enter your password more frequently during a session, and you may be unable to install or use certain Pocket Technologies. Cookies and other technologies make our Pocket Technologies easier to use and help us customize and personalize the services we provide based on your interests and activities. 

We may also use "pixel tags," "web beacons," "clear GIFs" or similar means (individually or collectively "Pixel Tags") in connection with our services to collect usage, demographic and geographical location data. A Pixel Tag is an electronic image, often a single pixel, that is ordinarily not visible to users and may be associated with cookies on a user’s hard drive. Pixel Tags allow us to count users who have visited certain pages on our Website, to deliver branded services and to help determine the effectiveness of promotional or advertising campaigns. 

#### COLLECTION OF INFORMATION FROM CHILDREN

We comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, which requires us to notify and obtain consent from a parent or guardian before we collect, use and disclose the personal information of anyone under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect any personal information from young people under the age of 13 without such consent and if we learn that we have inadvertently done so, we will promptly delete it. 

#### USE OF INFORMATION

We use the information we collect to provide our services, such as saving videos, articles or other content to Pocket and making such content available to you at a later time on any device that you use to access the Pocket Technologies. In addition, if you choose to use the Pocket Technologies to share content with another person, we will use the recipient's email address or user account information to provide that service, but we will not use that email address for any other purpose. We also use the information that you provide and that we collect to determine the format in which our content will be delivered to you, which format may differ depending on your device, and to provide other services based on the options you have selected in the Pocket application. If you choose to subscribe to our paid subscription service, we use your credit card information solely for processing payments. Your credit card information will not be stored by us except, for support purposes, we may store the credit card type, the expiration date, and the last four digits of the credit card. 

We use the information you provide to operate and improve the Pocket Technologies, and to deliver the other products and services we offer. For example, we may use your contact information to respond to your inquiries, to provide customer support and to supply any products or services you have requested. You may also opt in to receive communications from third parties that use the Pocket Technologies in conjunction with their products and services, or you may opt in to allow third parties to use some of the information we collect to customize the services they provide to you. For example, you may opt in to allow a third-party app to use information about the content you have saved to Pocket to suggest content that may be of interest to you. If you request information through the use of the Pocket Technologies, you may be contacted by us or by a third party to follow up on your request. For example, if you submit a question or make an inquiry through the Pocket website, you will use the information you provide in order to respond. 

We use non-identifying, aggregated information to analyze the manner in which the Pocket Technologies are used. Such aggregated information includes the manner in which videos, articles or content has been accessed, saved and shared. We may use aggregated information to offer a list of top sites or content, or to make suggestions to our users or to report on usage and trends. We may also analyze and use aggregated information to improve the products and services that we offer, and to develop new products and services. 

#### THIRD PARTY PRODUCTS AND SERVICES

We work with hundreds of third-party applications and a wide variety of devices and platforms. Although the Pocket Technologies may be used in conjunction with such third-party products and services, we are not affiliated with, and have no control over, such third parties. The Pocket Technologies also enable you to share videos, articles and information with persons over whom we have no control. 

Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. To the extent that you or we disclose your information to any third parties, including any third parties that provide products or services used in conjunction with the Pocket Technologies, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of your information. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control, or to people that we do not employ or manage. Please check the privacy policy of each third-party provider of products or services. 

#### SHARING OF INFORMATION

If you choose to make the content you save publicly available, we may share that information with others in accordance with the options you select. In addition, if you choose to use the Pocket Technologies to share videos, articles or other content with another person, we will send an email on your behalf to that person with a link to the content that you have chosen to share. We also share aggregated data and related usage information with third parties, including content providers, website operators, advertisers and publishers, but this aggregate information does not contain any personal information which can identify you or any other individual user. The sharing of aggregated data may include reports provided to third parties based on the information we collect and analyze. We do not control how third parties disclose or use the information we share with them. 

We do not share any personally identifiable information with any third-party provider of products and services that integrate with the Pocket Technologies. Nor do we share any other private or personal information unless you expressly agree that we may do so. For example, you may be informed that another app that you have downloaded wants to connect to your Pocket account. In some cases, such apps will request access to certain data in your Pocket account, such as your Pocket queue or your preferred topics, sites and authors (which we have developed based on the content you have saved to Pocket), so that they can customize their services. Before such access is provided, however, you will be asked to authorize the sharing of any such information. 

We may work with third parties that we refer to as internal service providers to facilitate or outsource one or more aspects of the products and services that we provide to you, and we may provide some of your private information directly to these internal service providers. For example, as discussed above, we may use a third party payment processor to process payments for our paid subscription service. The internal service providers are subject to confidentiality agreements with us and other legal restrictions that prohibit their use of the information we provide to them for any other purpose except to facilitate the specific outsourced operation, unless you have explicitly agreed or given your prior permission to them for additional uses. 

In the event that we or certain of our assets are acquired, user information may be included among the transferred assets. If this does occur, your information will remain subject to the terms and conditions of our Privacy Policy, unless our successor amends this policy as provided below. If our Privacy Policy is amended following an acquisition, you may be provided with the option to opt out so that our successor does not continue to use your private information. 

Although we strive to protect the private information of our users, we will release private information, including personally identifiable information, if required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary. Due to the existing regulatory environment, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be forced to disclose private information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, or users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect as a result of your use of the Pocket Technologies. Therefore, although we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private. 

#### SECURITY

We have agreements with third parties and have adopted other security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and/or unauthorized alteration of the information under our control or under the control of our service providers. Your personally identifiable information is protected by utilizing both online and offline security methods, including firewalls, passwords and restricted physical access to the places where your information is stored. It is possible, however, that a third party will circumvent such security measures, and we do not guarantee that our security measures will successfully prevent third parties from accessing the information we collect. In the event of a security breach involving your personal information, we will make any legally required disclosures to you in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, consistent with the legitimate interests of law enforcement, or any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system. 

#### PHISHING

Identity theft and the practice currently known as "phishing" are of great concern to Pocket. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is a top priority. We do not and will not, at any time, request your username, password, credit card information or national identification number in an unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. For more information about phishing, visit the Federal Trade Commission’s website. 

#### OPT-OUT

If you choose to make certain information public, but later wish to opt out and withdraw such consent, you may do so by changing your settings at <http://getpocket.com/privacy_controls>. If you have signed up to receive email from us, or if someone has asked us to share content with you, and you would like to avoid receiving such email in the future, you may opt-out of receiving it by using the unsubscribe feature on any of our email correspondence. We will try to communicate with you only according to your instructions, although it may take some time to process your request. 

If you have signed up to receive email from us and would like to avoid receiving such email in the future, you may opt-out of receiving it by using the unsubscribe feature on any of our email correspondence. We will try to communicate with you only according to your instructions, although it may take some time to process your request. 

#### UPDATING THE INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE

The Pocket application allows you to update or change the information you provided to us during registration. You may do so by logging in and choosing the option for "Edit My Account." The Advanced Option menu also allows you to clear saved links from your account. If you have any questions about updating the information you have provided to us, please contact us at **[privacy@getpocket.com](mailto:privacy@getpocket.com)**. 

#### AMENDMENTS TO POLICY

Please note this Privacy Policy will change from time to time. We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on our Website that you can access at [getpocket.com](http://getpocket.com/) or through the options or help menu of the Pocket application. All amended terms shall automatically be effective thirty (30) days after they are initially posted on the Website. If we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy that affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Website notifying users that our Privacy Policy has changed. Our use of your information shall be governed by the terms and conditions of our Privacy Policy in effect when you first use our application or thirty (30) after the terms are changed, as explained above. 

If you have questions about any of the provisions described above, please contact us at [privacy@getpocket.com](mailto:privacy@getpocket.com) or at the street address listed above.
